Dennou Boukenki
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Series Composition
Sekijima Mayori
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
Concept Design
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Kawami Takuya
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Takatori Hideaki
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Kachihide Yuki
Nomura Hiroshi
Director
Okajima Kunitoshi
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
Chief Director
Negishi Hiroshi
Production
침입자라고? 어떤 멍청한 놈이.
An invader? Call it a fool.
Penyusup? Tidak mungkin. Makhluk apa itu?
뭐야, 저거?
What's that?
Apa itu?
시간의 방랑자! 초록 머리 소년
Wanderer of Time!
The Boy with Green Hair
Pengelana Waktu! Lelaki Berambut Hijau
운석일까. 뭐라고 생각해?
Is that supposed to be a shooting star?
Mungkin itu meteor. Menurutmu itu apa?
식물 씨앗 같기도 한데...
I'd call it a plant seed.
Terlihat seperti biji tanaman bagiku.
식물? 이렇게 큰 게?
Plant? What plant has seed this big?
Tanaman? Sebesar ini?
어쨌든 가지고 가서 뭔지 알아 보자.
We'll take this back and find out what this is anyway.
Pokoknya, coba kita bawa dulu dan cari tahu.
잠깐! 류토의 함정일지도 모르잖아!
Stop! It might be a trap of Ryuto!
Tunggu dulu! Ini bisa saja jebakan Ryuto!
-류토?
-폭탄인지 뭔지 위험하잖아.
-Ryuto?
-Who knows it might be a bomb?
-Jebakannya?
-Entah bom atau apa. Tapi bisa jadi barang berbahaya.
생각한 대로 폭탄이야!
Yep, that's a bomb, run away!
Ternyata memang bom!
-아, 아기다!
-귀여워!
-A baby!
-How cute!
-Wah, bayi!
-Lucunya!
손 떼!
Take your hands off!
Jangan sentuh itu!
뭐야, 나오키!
Hey, Naoki!
Na-naoki!
이, 이 섬에는 우리 밖에 인간이 있을 리가 없어!
There's no human else than us in this island... supposedly!
D-di pulau ini seharusnya tidak ada manusia selain kita!
이렇게 내버려 두어도 괜찮다는 거야?
You're saying that he's fine like this?
Jadi maksudmu kita harus membiarkannya saja?
남자아이야.
The baby's a boy.
Wah, bayinya laki-laki.
누가 뭐래도 수상해! 이건 류토의 함정이야!
It is definitely suspicious! This must be a trap!
Benar-benar mencurigakan! Dia pasti jebakan Ryuto!
나도 볼래.
Show me too!
Perlihatkan ke aku juga, dong!
배가 고픈가 봐.
He must be hungry.
Dia sepertinya lapar.
어쩌지. 이 섬에 우유같은 건 없는데.
Too bad, there's no milk in this island.
Gawat juga. Di pulau ini tidak ada susu.
기저귀같은 건 있을 거야.
Well I saw a diaper.
Popok dan yang lainnya seharusnya ada.
괜찮아.
Don't cry.
Shh, shh.
착하지?
Good boy.
Anak baik.
서투를 거면 나한테 맡겨!
If you're bad at that, just leave it to me!
Kalau memang tidak bisa, serahkan saja padaku!
갓난아기는 이렇게 재워야 해.
This is how you make a baby sleep.
Begini cara membuat bayi tertidur.
울 필요 없어! 남자얘랬지? 으쌰으쌰으쌰.
Stop crying! He's a boy, right? Come on.
Jangan menangis! Kau laki-laki, kan? Shh, shh.
나오키!
Naoki!
여동생한테 맨날 했었으니까.
I did this to my sister all the time.
Aku sudah biasa merawat adikku soalnya.
다행이야. 코코넛 주스가 마음에 들었나 봐.
What a relief. He seems to like coconut juice.
Syukurlah. Dia sepertinya menyukai air kelapa.
어디서 온 걸까. 이상한 일도 다 있어.
I wonder where did he came from. This is totally unexpected.
Dia datang dari mana ya? Sungguh bayi yang misterius.
나오키가 말한 대로 류토의 함정일 수도.
Maybe he is a trap of Ryuto, as Naoki told!
Kalau misalnya seperti yang Naoki bilang, seandainya dia jebakan Ryuto--
아니야! 절대 아니야! 이놈은 괴물 따위가 아냐!
No way! I already rested my case! He cannot be a monster!
Bukan! Pasti bukan! Dia bukanlah monster!
내가 보장한다. 알겠냐!
I guarantee it, you know!
Aku bisa jamin itu! Ya, kan!
배불러서 졸린 거 같아.
He seems to be full and sleepy!
Sepertinya ia kenyang dan sedang tertidur.
아, 정말이네, 잠들었어!
Hey, that's true! He's sleeping!
Wah, iya, dia tertidur!
역시 귀여워.
Cute, as always!
Lucu, kan?
뭐야, 저거?
What's that?
Apa itu?
같이 가 보자.
Let's go find out.
Semuanya, ayo kita coba lihat.
대체 어떻게 이런 일이?
How did this happen?
Bagaimana ini bisa terjadi?
저 아기가 나타난 거하고 뭔가 관련이 있다면...
Maybe that baby has something to do with this...
Sepertinya ada hubungannya dengan kemunculan bayi itu.
그럴 리가!
That's impossible!
Itu mustahil!
아오이야!
That was Aoi!
Yang tadi itu Aoi!
아오이!
Aoi!
-아오이!
-켄토!
-Aoi!
-Kento!
-뭔 일이야?
-몰라. 갑자기 빛이 나.
-What happened?
-I don't know. He started to shine all of the sudden.
-Apa yang terjadi?
-Aku tidak tahu. Tiba-tiba ia bersinar begitu saja.
-뭐하는 거지?
-단말에서 무언가 정보를 받고 있나 봐.
-What's he doing?
-He looks like he's receiving some data from a terminal.
-Apa yang sedang ia lakukan?
-Sepertinya ia mengambil data dari terminal itu.
하늘.
Sky.
Langit.
말했어!
He spoke!
Dia berbicara?!
넌 대체 뭐야?
What are you?
Sebenarnya makhluk apa kau?
-크로루.
-말할 줄 알아?
-Kuroru.
-You know how to speak?
-Kau bisa mengerti bahasa kami?
단말에서 배웠어요.
I learned from the terminal.
Aku mempelajarinya dari terminal.
모두 감사합니다.
Thank you, everyone.
Terima kasih, semuanya.
크로루는 어디서 왔어?
Where did you came from, Kuroru?
Kuroru datang dari mana?
내 세계는 이제 존재하지 않습니다. 전멸했어요. 백만 년 전에.
My world does not exist any more. It was annihilated. A million years ago.
Duniaku sudah tidak ada lagi. Ia dihancurkan sejuta tahun yang lalu.
-백만 년 전?
-대체 뭔 일이 있던 거야?
-A million years?
-What happened back then?
-Sejuta tahun yang lalu?
-Apa yang sebenarnya terjadi?
우리 전뇌세계가 있었을 때 컴퓨터 바이러스에게 침략을 받았습니다.
When my cyberspace existed, it was invaded by a computer virus.
Saat itu, dunia maya kami diserang oleh sebuah virus komputer.
데리트로스라는 컴퓨터 바이러스.
A computer virus named Deletloss.
Sebuah virus komputer bernama Deletloss.
이 전뇌세계는 데리트로스가 지배한다.
I will take this cyberspace from now on.
Dunia maya ini akan dikuasai oleh Deletloss.
데리트로스의 전뇌세계 공격은 저희가 살던 세계에 치명적인 타격을 주어서
Deletloss' attack on the cyber world has damaged the world we live in so deeply and
Serangan Deletloss di dunia maya telah merusak dunia tempat kami tinggal habis-habisan.
돌아갈 수 없게 되었습니다.
we couldn't go back any more.
Sehingga kami tidak bisa kembali lagi.
그런 일이 있었구나. 백만 년 전에 데리트로스가 있었다니.
That's a terrible story. Knowing that Deletloss was there a million years ago...
Mengerikan sekali mengetahui bahwa Deletloss sudah ada sejuta tahun yang lalu...
잠깐. 방금 태어난 크로루가 왜 그런 걸 다 알아?
Hey, how can you know about all that, after being born just a moment ago?
Tunggu dulu. Mengapa Kuroru yang baru saja lahir mengetahui hal itu?
아, 그렇습니까. 당신들은 성장 컨트롤을 할 수 없는 것 같네요.
Ah, I forgot to tell you that I can control my growth, which you cannot do.
Eh? Oh, iya. Kalian tidak bisa mengendalikan pertumbuhan kalian, ya?
-컨트롤?
우리 종족은
-Control?
-Our species can
-Mengendalikan?
-Spesies kami
자신이 살 수 있는 환경을 찾을 때까지 저 모습으로 잠들어 있는 것이 가능합니다.
stay hibernated until we find an environment that we can live on.
akan terus hibernasi dalam bentuk itu hingga menemukan lingkungan yang cocok bagi kami.
-씨앗의 모양으로?
-넌 백만 년 동안 떠돌고 있던 거구나.
-In a form of seed?
-You're floating on the space for a million years.
-Dengan bentuk seperti biji itu?
-Jadi, kau sudah mengembara selama satu juta tahun?
전뇌세계를. 단 혼자서.
Through cyberspace. Without any companion.
Di dunia maya. Sendiri.
불쌍해.
That's miserable.
Kasihan sekali.
하늘을 보고 살아있고 다시 누군가하고 이야기한다는 것이 가능하다는 것은
To look at the sky, to live, and to talk with someone,
Bisa melihat langit, bernafas, dan berbicara dengan seseorang saja
마치 꿈 같습니다.
is just like a dream.
sudah seperti mimpi bagiku.
크로루도 데리트로스하고 싸워 왔으면 우리 선배구나.
Kuroru has been fighting against Deletloss. He's our teacher.
Berarti, Kuroru juga telah bertarung melawan Deletloss. Dia senior kita.
어?
What?
Eh?
우리도 데리트로스하고 싸우고 있어. 글라디온이나 웹나이트들하고 함께.
We are fighting against Deletloss too. Along with Webknights including Gladion.
Kami juga bertarung melawan Deletloss bersama dengan Gladion dan Webknight lain.
응.
Right.
Benar.
글라디온?
Gladion?
글라디온! 틀림없어. 글라디온이다.
Gladion! There's no doubt that he is Gladion.
Gladion! Tidak salah lagi, itu dia.
백만 년 전의 전뇌세계에 데리트로스가 있고, 그리고, 글라디온까지도!
There was Deletloss in the cyberspace a million years ago, and now Gladion too!
Ada Deletloss di dunia maya sejuta tahun setelah itu, dan juga Gladion!
그럴 리가! 백만 년 전의 크로루가 어떻게?
No way! How do you know that, after coming from a million years ago?
Mustahil! Kenapa Kuroru yang dari sejuta tahun yang lalu bisa tahu?
글라디온 아는 거야, 크로루?
Do you know Gladion, Kuroru?
Apa kau kenal Gladion, Kuroru?
네 세계에도 글라디온이? 말해 줘, 크로루.
Was Gladion there in your world too? Tell us, Kuroru.
Apa ada Gladion juga di duniamu? Beritahu kami, Kuroru.
그건,
That is,
Tentang itu,
쟌!
Jean!
사라졌어!
He's gone!
Ia menghilang!
Brought to you by Subdiver
쟌은 어디로 사라졌어?
Where did Jean disappeared to?
Jean menghilang ke mana?
봐봐!
Look!
Lihat itu!
하늘이!
The sky!
Langitnya!
소멸의 원인은 이 소년이야뾰꼬.
The reason of disappearance is this boy-pyoko.
Penyebab dibalik kehilangan ini adalah anak itu-pyoko.
가상 공간에 있는 버추얼 다이버랜드가 크로루하고 반응하고 있어.
Virtual Diverland in a virtual space is reacting to Kuroru.
Virtual Diverland, yang berada di ruang buatan, mengalami reaksi penolakan terhadap benda asing yang disebut Kuroru itu-pyoko.
크로루가 있는 한 버추얼 다이버랜드의 소멸은 계속될 거야뾰꼬.
As long as Kuroru's here, Virtual Diverland will keep disappearing-pyoko.
Selama Kuroru di sini, penghilangan di Virtual Diverland akan terus berlanjut-pyoko.
너무해, 카론! 크로루는 백만 년을 떠돌다가 겨우 이 곳에 도착했잖아!
That's too much, Karon, to say to a boy who was alone for a million years!
Itu berlebihan, Karon! Kuroru yang berkelana selama sejuta tahun itu baru saja tiba di sini!
켄토! 지금까지의 반응와는 차원이 다른 적이 대단한 속도로 접근 중이다!
Kento! An enemy that has incomparably high energy reaction is approaching in insane speed!
Kento! Sebuah musuh yang reaksinya berbeda dari biasanya sedang mendekat dengan kecepatan tinggi!
네가 존재하기 때문에 백만 년 전의 적이 추적했다는 거야?
So an enemy back then has followed you?
Jadi, dengan adanya dirimu, musuh saat sejuta tahun yang lalu juga mengejarmu, ya?
그렇습니다. 제라드.
That's right. Its name is Gerald.
Benar. Ia adalah Gerald.
가상 공간의 균형이 무너져 배리어의 효과가 낮아진 지금 버추얼 다이버랜드는 무방비다. 서둘러, 켄토!
The balance of this virtual space collapsed, and it lowered the effect of our barrier.
Keseimbangan ruang buatan ini hancur, sehingga efek barier-nya berkurang.
Now, Virtual Diverland is now without protection. Hurry up, Kento!
Sekarang, Virtual Diverland tidak dilindungi oleh apapun. Bergegaslah, Kento!
알았어, 글라디온!
Got it, Gladion!
Aku mengerti, Gladion!
제라드는 강적입니다. 제 세계를, 동료를 말살한 증오하는 적입니다.
Gerald is a strong enemy that I abhor. It annihilated my world and my friends.
Gerald adalah musuh kuat yang kubenci. Ia telah melenyapkan duniaku dan teman-temanku.
크로루. 동료의 원수는 우리가 갚아 줄게! 가자, 나오키!
Kuroru, we'll revenge for your friends! Let's go, Naoki!
Kuroru, kita akan membalaskan dendam teman-temanmu! Ayo pergi, Naoki!
그래!
Got it!
Baik!
할 거지, 나오키?
Will you do this, Naoki?
Sudah siap, Naoki?
당연하지.
Of course.
Ya, tentu saja.
매지컬 스테이션에 플러그 잇!
To Magical Station, Plug It!
Menuju Magical Station, Plug It!
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
긴급 발진 대기중.
Emergency dispatch, standby.
Siap untuk diluncurkan.
글라디온, 출동.
Gladion, shoot.
글라디온, 백만 년 전에도 데리트로스하고 싸웠었어?
Gladion, did you fought against Deletloss even a million years ago?
Gladion, apakah kamu melawan Deletloss juga sejuta tahun yang lalu?
글라디온!
Gladion!
ケント。時がくれば必ず話す。必ず
켄토. 때가 되면 꼭 말해 줄게. 꼭.
Kento, I'll tell you when the time comes. I promise.
Kento, akan kuberitahu saat waktunya tiba. Aku janji.
오? 그 때 그 제라드라니 재밌군.
Oh? That Gerald has came? That's pretty interesting.
Oh? Ternyata Gerald yang itu. Menarik juga.
네놈에게 적당한 전투 필드를 내가 용인해 주지.
I'll let you use a field specifically designated for you.
Akan kusiapkan medan pertarungan yang cocok bagimu.
놈이야!
It's him!
Itu dia!
단숨에 끝내버리겠어!
He won't be there in no time!
Ayo kita selesaikan ini secepatnya!
웹체인지! 글라디온, 파이터 모드!
Webchange! Gladion, Fighter Mode!
웹체인지! 드라그온, 파이터 모드!
Webchange! Dragwon, Fighter Mode!
그란발칸!
Granvulcan!
블랙 홀 캐논!
Black Hole Cannon!
와이버리온!
Wyverion!
글라디온! 빅토리 모드!
Gladion! Victory Mode!
웹체인지! 와이버리온, 윙 모드!
Webchange! Wyverion, Wing Mode!
빅토리 글라디온!
Victory Gladion!
쇼우!
Shou!
그렇습니까. 역시 내가 원인으로...
I see. I am the reason.
Begitu. Jadi, memang aku penyebabnya.
아오이, 카이토, 헤어질 시간이 왔습니다.
Aoi, Kaito, time for separation has come.
Aoi, Kaito, sepertinya sudah saatnya kita berpisah.
헤어진다니 뭔 말이야?
Separate? What do you mean by that?
Apa maksudmu dengan berpisah?
너, 설마!
Are you going to-
Jangan-jangan, kau bermaksud-
이게 내 진짜 모습이야.
This is my true form.
Ini adalh wujudku yang sebenarnya.
그럼 이만.
Farewell.
Selamat tinggal.
너희들하고 만나서 기뻤다.
It was a big pleasure meeting you.
Aku senang dapat bertemu dengan kalian semua.
-크로루!
-Kuroru!
뭐야?!
What the?!
Apa?!
-크로루!
-너냐!
-Kuroru!
-It's you!
-Itu kamu!
-크로루!
-Kuroru!
나오키!
Naoki!
웹체인지! 드라그온, 어택 모드!
Webchange! Dragwon, Attack Mode!
글라디온! 캐논 모드!
Gladion! Cannon Mode!
슈퍼 블랙 홀 캐논!
Super Black Hole Cannon!
크로루...
Kuroru...
크로루는 살아 있어. 꽃의 모습으로 수만 년이고 수억 년이고.
Kuroru lives. In a form of flower, for millions and billions of years.
Kuroru akan terus hidup dalam bentuk bunga ini. Entah berapa lamapun.
새 고향을... 찾을 때까지...
Until we find a new home for him.
Hingga kita menemukan rumah baru untuknya.
크로루... 우리가 돌아가게 될 때 꼭 널 우리 세계에 데려가 줄게.
Kuroru... when we get to go back, we'll take you along with us.
Kuroru... saat kami kembali, kami pasti akan membawamu ke dunia kami.
반드시.
Right.
Ya.
그럴 거야.
We will.
Itu benar.
약속.
It's a promise.
Kami janji
그 때까지 편히 쉬어.
Until then, take a rest.
Hingga waktu itu tiba, istirahatlah yang cukup.
Screenplay
Araki Ken'ichi
Storyboarding
Staging
Takata Atsushi
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Gladion
Arisugawa Aoi
Asaba Naoki
Takeuchi Junko
Kobayashi Yumiko
Sugita Tomokazu
Kikuchi Shiho
Kurachi Shou
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Jean J. Jekyll
Nakai Masataka
Yuuki Kaito
Takagi Reiko
Kuroru
Naruse Makoto
Ryuto
Yoshino Hiroyuki
Voice Actor
Dragwon
Kawada Shinji
Deletloss
Tachiki Fumihiko
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Oikawa Neko
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kouno Yougo
Singer
Kageyama Hironobu
Insert Song
Lyrics
Composer
Arranger
Kyouda Seiichi
Singer
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
Production
Thank you for watching!
다음 이야기 미리보기
Preview for Next Episode
Episode Selanjutnya
정신 차리고 보니 내가 둘이나 있었어.
When I finally got grip of myself, I found two of myself.
Tanpa kusadari, diriku ada dua.
야! 왜 내가 둘이나 있는 거야! 유우키 켄토, 그건 나뿐이야!
Hey! Why the heck are there two of me? Yuuki Kento, that is me!
Woy! Kenapa ada dua aku? Yuuki Kento itu cuma aku seorang!
모두, 이 가짜를! 뭐? 누가 누군지 모르겠다고?
Let's get rid of this phony- what?! You can't identify who's the real one and who's not?!
Semuanya, ayo kita habisi gadungan-- apa?! Tidak ada yang bisa membedakan kami berdua?
진짜는 나라고! 믿어, 좀!
I'm the real one! Believe me!
Akulah yang asli! Percaya padaku!
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !